Register to The Thomas de Hartmann Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Orchestral Music, I.B
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57, arr.] Concerto pour violoncelle et orchestre / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1938., 1 score (36 p.) + 1 part (12 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 56)
      Arr. cello and piano.
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57, arr.], 1 score (51 p.); 24 x 32 cm. (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57, arr.] Concerto for violoncelle II reduction., 1 score (2 p.); 25 x 32 cm. (Box 6, Folder 57)
      From 2nd movement.
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57, arr.], 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 57)
      Manuscript, transparency.
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57], 16 parts; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57], 51 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 6, Folder 59)
      Manuscript, transparencies of parts.
      Some sections cut out.
    - [Concertos, violoncello, orchestra, op. 57], 1 score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 6, Folder 60)
      Excerpt from orchestral score.
      5 p. of manuscript notes enclosed, 1 copy only.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 39] Concerto pour piano et orchestre, op. 39 / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1939., 1 score (138 p.); 37 cm. (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 39] Concerto pour piano et orchestre, op. 39 / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1939., 1 score (138 p.); 36 cm. (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 1, op. 39, arr.] Concerto pour piano et orchestre / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1951., 1 score (70 p.); 32 cm. (Box 7, Folder 63)
      Plate no: 3471
      Arr. for two pianos.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 61, arr.], 1 score (80 p.); 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 64)
      2 copies, 2nd copy incomplete.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 61, (sketches)], 64 p. of music in 5 quires. (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 61], 32 parts; 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 66)
      String parts.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 61], 28 parts; 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 67)
      Brass, wind, percussion, and harp parts.
    - [Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 61], 51 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - [Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 66], 1 score (94 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 69)
      Annotations in pen.
      (Boosey and Hawkes rental library)
    - [Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 66] Violin concerto "Symphonie concertante for violin and orchestre.", 1 score (94 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - [Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 66, arr.], 1 score (46 p.); 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 70)
      Arr. for violin and piano.
    - [Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 66] Concerto for violin., 1 part (13 p.); 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 71)
      Part for solo violin.
    - [Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 66], 56 parts; 35 cm. (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - [Fantasie-concerto, contrabass, orchestra, op. 64], 1 score (72 p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 73)
      Annotations in blue pencil.
      At end: Dernier Samedi de Novembre 1944 Garches
    - [Fantasie-concerto, contrabass, orchestra, op. 64, arr.], 1 score (24 p.); 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 74)
      Arr. for bass and piano.
      Thomas de Hartmann notes in French with English translation.
      At end: 4 Fevrier 1942 Garches
      2 versions.
    - [Fantasie-concerto, contrabasse, orchestra, op. 64], 28 parts; 34 cm. (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - [Gurla, op. 72] La gurla: concerto pour harpe et orchestre., 1 part (21 p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 76)
      Part for solo harp.
    - [Gurla, op. 72] Rapsodie slave (d'après P. Mérimé), 1 score (59 p.); 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 76)
      For harp and orchestra.
    - [Gurla, op. 72] La gurla: concerto pour harpe et orchestre., 11 parts; 34 cm. (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - [Gurla, op. 72, arr.] La gurla pour harpe et orchestre., 1 score (47 p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 77)
      Arr. for harp and piano.
    - [Gurla, op. 72 (sketches)], 3 p. of music in 1 quire. (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - [Koladky, op. 59] Koladky: Noëls ucrainiens, chant spirituel., 1 score (45 p.); 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 78)
      Manuscript and typescript notes, 1 copy only.
      (Presser rental library)
    - [Koladky, op. 59], 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - [Koladky, op. 59], 36 parts; 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - [Koladky, op. 59], 23 parts; 33 cm. (Box 10, Folder 81)
      Woodwind, brass, and percussion parts.
    - [Koladky, op. 59], 54 parts; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - [Scherzo fantastique], 1 score (34 p.); 35 cm (Box 10, Folder 83)
      Belaieff sticker on front.
    - [Scherzo fantastique], 1 score (34 p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - [Suite, orchestra, op. 62] Suite pour grand orchestre, op. 62., 1 score (115 p.); 38 cm. (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - [Suite, orchestra, op. 62 (sketches)], 106 p. of music in 6 quires. (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 50] Symphonie - poème, op. 50., 1 score (311 p.); 40 cm. (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 50] Symphonie - poème, op. 50., 15 parts; 38 cm. (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 50] Symphonie - poème, op. 50., 15 parts; 38 cm. (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 50] Symphonie - poème, op. 50., 20 parts; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 90-91)
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, op. 50] Symphonie - poème, op. 50., 14 parts; 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - [Symphonies, no. 2, op. 68] Le dit du soleil: 2nd symphonie-poème., 1 score (117 p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 93)
      Typescript note inside cover, both copies.
      At beginning: à la memoire de Mitrofan Petrovitch Belaieff. [1 copy only]
    - [Symphonies, no. 2, op. 68] Le dit du soleil: 2nd symphonie-poème., 1 score (117 p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 94)
    - [Symphonies, no. 2, op. 68] Le dit du soleil: 2nd symphonie-poème., 34 parts; 32 cm. (Box 13, Folder 95)
    - [Symphonies, no. 3, op. 85] 3rd symphonie-poème, op. 85., 1 score (109 p.); 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 96)
      Typescript notes, 1 copy only.
    - [Symphonies, no. 3, op. 85 (sketches)], 28 p. of music in 3 quires. (Box 14, Folder 97)
    - [Symphonies, no. 3, op. 85], 38 parts; 33 cm. (Box 14, Folder 98)
      String, percussion, and keyboard parts.
    - [Symphonies, no. 3, op. 85], 23 parts; 33 cm. (Box 14, Folder 99)
      Brass and woodwind parts.
    - [Symphonies, no. 4, op. 90] Quatrième symphonie - poème., 1 score (39 p.); 39 cm. (Box 14, Folder 100)
    - [Symphonies, no. 4, op. 90] Sinfonie nr. 4 in einem satz / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1979., 1 miniature score (39 p.); 19 cm. (Box 14, Folder 101)
      Plate no. 4031
      Negative prints, 1 copy only.
    - [Symphonies, no. 4, op. 90 (sketches)], 75 p. of music in 3 quires. (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - [Symphonies, no. 4, op. 90], 55 parts; 32 cm. (Box 15, Folder 103)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58] Fairy Tales., 1 score (59 p.); 39 cm. (Box 15, Folder 104)
      2 p. typescript introduction with press comments.
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 1 score (61 p.); 39 cm. (Box 15, Folder 104)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 1 score (61 p.); 38 cm. (Box 15, Folder 104)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 1 score (59 p.); 39 cm. (Box 15, Folder 105)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58 (sketches)], 37 p. of music in 1 quire. (Box 15, Folder 106)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 36 parts; 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 107)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 26 parts; 34 cm. (Box 16, Folder 108)
      Woodwinds, brass, percussion, and keyboard.
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 63 parts; 37 cm. (Box 16, Folder 109)
    - [Russian fairy tales, op. 58], 27 parts; 32 cm. (Box 16, Folder 110)
  - Chamber Music, I.C
    - [Chanson sentimentale], 1 score (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 17, Folder 111)
      For treble instrument and piano.
      On cover: Th. Kross [Thomas de Hartmann pseudonym]
    - [Melodies, treble instrument, piano], 1 score (3 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 111)
    - [Esther, op. 76. Selections, arr.] Danse assyrienne (Esther), 1 score (9 p.) + 1 part (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 112)
      For violin and piano.
    - [Esther, op. 76. Selections, arr.] Danse d'Esther., 3 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 17, Folder 113)
      Contents: Hellénique -- Scyte.
      For violin and piano [only 10 m. of piano]
    - [Esther, op. 76. Selections, arr.] Danses d'Esther: Scyte., 1 score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 113)
    - [Esther, op. 76. Selections, arr.] Danses de l'opéra "Esther.", 1 score (11 p.); 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 113)
      Contents: Assirienne -- Parthe.
    - [Esther, op. 76. Selections, arr.] Hellénique (Esther), 1 score (2 p.) + 1 part (1 p.); 34 cm. (Box 17, Folder 113)
    - [Kobsa] La kobsa: deux musiques de veilleurs ukrainiens pour violoncelle solo., 1 score (2 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 113)
      Bound with: Deux melodies for treble instrument and piano and Mendelssohn's Chant au rouet transcribed for cello and piano.
    - [Quasi variations, op. 75] Trio: Quasi variations., 1 score (47 p.); 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 114)
      For flute, violin, and piano.
      At end: Garches 1946 l'été
    - [Sonatas, violoncello, piano, op 63] Sonate pour violoncelle et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1948., 1 score (51 p.) + 1 part (18 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 115)
      Plate no: 3448
      At end: Garches 1941
    - [Sonatas, violoncello, piano, op. 63] Sonate pour violoncelle et piano., 1 score (57 p.); 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 116)
      At beginning: à mon ami Gerard Hekking
    - [Sonatas, violoncello, piano, op. 63], 1 score (51 p.) + 1 part (18 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 117)
      Transparencies.
    - [Sonatas, violoncello, piano, op. 63], 1 score (58 p.) + 1 part (19 p.); 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 117)
    - [Sonatas, violin, piano, op. 51] Sonate pour violon et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Frankfurt: Belaieff, 1957., 1 score (44 p.) + 1 part (15 p.); 31 cm. (Box 17, Folder 118)
      Plate no: R.132-59.L
    - [Sonatas, violin, piano, op. 51], 1 score (78 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 119)
    - [Sonatas, violin, piano, op. 51], 1 score (44 p.) + 1 part (15 p.); 31 cm. (Box 17, Folder 120)
    - [Unidentified (sketches)], 14 p. of music; 27 cm. (Box 17, Folder 120)
  - Band Music, I.D
    - [Esther, op. 76. Lament of the daughters of Zion, arr.] Lament of the daughters of Zion (from the musical tragedy "Esther"), 1 score (13 p.); 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 121)
      Arr. for band.
    - [Esther, op. 76. Selections, arr.] Pagan dances from the musical tragedy "Esther.", 1 score (35 p.); 63 cm. (Box 17, Folder 122)
      Contents: Scythe -- Hellenic -- Assyrian -- Parthian.
      Arr. for Band.
    - [Esther, op. 76. Prayer for the people of Israel, arr.] Prayer for the people of Israel (musical tragedy "Esther"), 1 score (7 p.); 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 123)
    - [Scherzo-fantasy] Scherzo-fantasy (the ghost plane), 1 score (30 p.); 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 123)
      For band.
  - Piano Music, I.E
    - [Contes russes] Douze contes russes / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Frankfurt: Belaieff, 1937., 24 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 17, Folder 124)
      Plate no: 3410
      Annotations in pencil by Thomas de Hartmann, 1 copy only.
      Typescript introduction (2 p.), 1 copy only.
      1 copy is incomplete.
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie. Selections, arr.] [Title in Russian], 13 p. of music; 27 x 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 125)
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie. Selections, arr.] Les forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie, opéra pour le théâtre de marionettes., 8 p. of music; 28 cm. (Box 17, Folder 125)
      Contents: Menuet -- Gavotte.
    - [Forces de l'amour et de la sorcellerie. Selections, arr.] Divertissement pour clavecin ou piano., 10 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 18, Folder 126)
      Contents: Prelude (le triton) -- Gavotte -- Menuet -- La grenouille -- Marche turque.
      Annotations in pencil (1 p.)
    - [Humoresque viennoise], 7 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 18, Folder 127)
    - [Lumière noire, op. 74] Lumière noire pour piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Frankfurt: Belaieff, 1948., 8 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 128)
      Plate no: 3480
    - [Lumière noire, op. 74], 11 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 129)
      Manuscript notes on cover.
    - [Nocturnes, piano, op. 84] Two nocturnes, piano solo / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Frankfurt: Belaieff, 1955., 22 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 18, Folder 130)
      Plate no: 3476
    - [Nocturnes, piano, op. 84] Two nocturnes for piano., 13 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 131)
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Hymns from a great temple], 19 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 132)
      Copyright 1950.
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Journey to inaccessible places], 23 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 132)
      Copyright 1970.
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Rituals of a sufi order], 19 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 132)
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Seekers of the truth], 40 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 132)
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Selections], 21 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 18, Folder 133)
      27 short pieces for piano.
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Selections], 7 p. of music; 28 to 36 cm. (Box 18, Folder 134)
    - [Piano music (Gurdjieff). Selections], 1 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 18, Folder 134)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 1, op. 67] Sonate., 27 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 135)
      At end: 15 Décembre 1942 Garches
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 1, op. 67] Sonate., 27 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 136)
      At end: 15 Décember 1942 Garches
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 2, op. 82] Deuxième sonate pour piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- London: Boosey and Hawkes, 1956., 28 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 18, Folder 137)
      Plate no: 18332
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 2, op. 82] II piano sonata., 20 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 137)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 2, op. 82] 20 p. of music; 35 cm., 20 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 138)
      At end: Rawdon. 10 [Sept.] 1951.
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 2, op. 82 (sketches)], 9 p. of music in 1 quire. (Box 18, Folder 138)
    - [Unidentified (sketches)], 24 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 138)
      Includes: holograph sketches, a reconstructed score, and 1 quire of fragments.
  - Vocal Music, I.F
    - [À la lune, op. 11] À la lune pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Paris: Editions Musicales, 1937., 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 139)
      Plate no: R.195.L
      English text by Shelley.
      French translation by S. Bienaimé.
      Russian translation by K. Balmont.
    - [Ballade, op. 47a] Ballade pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1938., 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 140)
      Plate no: 3416
      Russian text by G. Adamovitch.
      English translation by M. Volkonsky.
      See also: Song is born, op. 47b.
    - [Barrel organ girl] The barrel organ girl (Marina Lvetaeva), 1 score (3 p.); 33 cm. (Box 18, Folder 141)
      Russian text by Marina Lvetaeva.
      English translation, 1 copy only.
      For voice and piano.
    - [Chansons Espagnoles, op. 19] Deux chansons espagnoles., 1 score (8 p.); 32 cm. (Box 18, Folder 142)
    - [Chansonette], 37 p. of music; various sizes. (Box 18, Folder 143)
      Collection of short piano solos and songs for voice and piano.
      Contents: Arizona -- Andantino -- Tempo di valse -- Allegro -- La chanson de vénetien mort -- Quand l'amour -- Crépuscule -- Romance.
    - [Chant de la mère d'un conscrit, op. 47c] Chant de la mère d'un conscrit pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1938., 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 144)
      Plate no: 3422
      Russian text by M. Zvetaieff.
      French and English translations by M. D. Calvocoressi.
    - [Chants bulgares, op. 46] Chants bulgares pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1938., 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 145)
      Plate no: 3417
      Russian text by C. Balmont.
    - [Choréographie], 1 part (1 p.); 32 cm. (Box 18, Folder 145)
      French text by S. Moreux.
      Vocal line only.
    - [Commentaires, Pour Ulysse, op. 71] Six commentaires pour Ulysse de James Joyce pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1948., 1 score (30 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 146)
      Plate no: 3461
      French text.
    - [Commentaires, Pour Ulysse, op. 71] Six commentaires pour Ulysse de James Joyce pour chant et piano., 1 score (33 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 147)
    - [Commentaires, Pour Ulysse, op. 71] Six commentaires pour Ulysse de James Joyce pour chant et piano., 1 score (33 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 148)
    - [Commentaires, Pour Ulysse, op. 71] Six commentaires pour Ulysse de James Joyce pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1948., 1 score (30 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 148)
      Photocopy.
    - [Cranes, op. 21] Cranes for voice and piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1955., 1 score (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 19, Folder 149)
      Plate no: XII
      Text by V. Zota.
    - [En l'herbier d'Hélène], 1 score (3 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 150)
      Russian and French words.
    - [Fragment de Proust] Fragment de Proust (À l'hombre des jeunes filles en fleures - Les trois arbres), 1 score (19 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 151)
    - [Fragment de Proust] Fragment de Proust (À l'hombre des jeunes filles en fleures - Les trois arbres), 1 score (24 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 152)
    - [Fragment de Proust] 2nd fragment de Proust., 1 score (9 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 153)
      At end: 18 Mars 1948 Garches.
    - [Maori songs, op. 12] Chants maoris., 1 score (12 p.); 33 cm. (Box 19, Folder 154)
      On cover: Old version
    - [Maori songs, op. 15] Chants maoris., 1 score (13 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 155)
      French translation.
      Contents: Rani -- Chant d'amour -- Anéantissement.
    - [Melodies, op. 17] Three melodies., 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 156)
      Russian text by A. Achmatova.
    - [Paysages tristes, op. 69] Sept paysages tristes., 7 scores (30 p.); 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 157)
      Contents: Soleils couchants -- Crépuscule du soir mystique -- Promenade sentimentale -- Nuit du walpurgis classique -- Chanson d'automne -- L'heure du berger -- Le rossignol.
    - [Paysages tristes, op. 69] Sept paysages tristes., 1 score (31 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 158)
    - [Paysages tristes, op. 69] Sept paysages tristes., 1 score (36 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - [Paysages tristes, op. 69] Sept paysages tristes., 1 score (30 p.); 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 160)
      Contents: Soleils couchants -- crépuscule du soir mystique -- promenade sentimentale -- nuit du walpurgis classique -- chanson d'automne -- L'heure du berger -- Le rossignol.
    - [Poèmes de Shelley, op. 52 #1] Trois poèmes de Shelley pour chant et piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Paris: Editions Musicales, 1936., 3 scores (24 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 161)
      Plate nos: R.110.L, R.111.L, R.112.L
      Contents: Hymn of Pan -- Time -- The Indian serenade.
      At end: Paris 1936
    - [Poet's love, op. 59] A poet's love, nine poems by Pushkin for voice and piano / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1936., 1 score (45 p.); 31 cm. (Box 19, Folder 162)
      Plate no: 3497
      French translation by M. Chatellier.
      English translation by J. George.
      (Boosey and Hawkes rental library) 1 copy only.
    - [Poet's love, op. 59] Love of the poet., 1 score (25 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 163)
      Russian text by Pushkin.
      French and English translations, 1 copy only.
    - [Pour chanter à la route d'Assise] Pour chanter à la route d'Assise / Thomas de Hartmann. -- New York: Boosey and Hawkes, 1955., 1 score (2 p.); 31 cm. (Box 19, Folder 164)
      Plate no: IX
      English translation.
    - [Pour danser], 1 score (2 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 165)
      French text by T. Kross [Thomas de Hartmann pseudonym]
    - [Song is born, op. 47b] A song is born / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1938., 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 166)
      Plate no: 3421
      See also: Ballade, op. 47a.
    - [Songs. Selections], 1 score (11 p.); 33 cm. (Box 19, Folder 167)
      Contents: Dumka -- Zapretnost -- Bysokaia slova.
    - [Songs] Two songs., 1 score (5 p.); 36 cm. (Box 19, Folder 168)
      Russian text.
    - [Songs, op. 17. Vision de Pouchkine] Vision de Pouchkine / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1938., 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 169)
      Plate no: 3415
      English words by M. D. Calvocoressi.
    - [Sonnet de Ronsard, op. 54] Sonnet de Ronsard (Les amours de Cassandre) / Thomas de Hartmann. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1953., 1 score (4 p.); 31 cm. (Box 19, Folder 170)
      Plate no: R.131-4.L
      French text with English translation.
    - [Stepenny], 1 score (2 p.); 27 cm (Box 19, Folder 170)
      On cover: Ecclesiastical singing for I. K. Denison.
      Vocal part with sketch of piano accompaniment.
    - [Ympo], 1 score (3 p.); 23 x 31 cm. (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - [Unidentified], 1 score (5 p.); 27 cm. (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - [Unidentified], 1 score (2 p.); 25 x 32 cm. (Box 19, Folder 172)
  - Choral Music, I.G
    - [Tramuntana] La tramuntana / J. Gual., 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 19, Folder 173)
      For SATB.
      On cover: à Pau Casals.
    - [Violets on Broadway (sketches)], 1 score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 19, Folder 173)
      English text.
      At beginning: chorus. refrain.
  - Film Music, I.H
    - [Kriss], 1 score (271 p.); 29 cm. (Box 20, Folder 174)
      For chamber ensemble.
    - [New York], 1 score (32 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 175)
      For orchestra.
    - [New York, arr.], 1 score (66 p.); 32 cm. (Box 20, Folder 175)
      Arr. for chamber ensemble.
    - [New York], 22 parts; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 176)
    - [Romniana], 52 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 20, Folder 177)
      Contents: Rapsodie onkraienne -- Idich -- Nerisaca -- Coanza fox -- My dear Dorothy -- The charming Anny -- Far Texas.
  - Transcriptions of Music by Other Composers, I.I
    - [Wohltemperierte Klavier, 1. T. Selections, arr.] Deux preludes de J.S. Bach., Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 score (6 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 111)
      Transcribed for cello and piano by Thomas de Hartmann.
    - [Organ music. Selections, arr.] Preludes et fugues de J.S. Bach., Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 score (64 p.); 33 cm. (Box 20, Folder 178)
      Arr. for orchestra by Thomas de Hartmann.
      At beginning: 2 p. of typescript notes in French.
    - [Wohltemperierte Klavier, 1. T. Selections, arr.] Deux preludes., Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; 1 score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - [Berceuse no. 5, op. 1] Berceuse (mélodie) op. 1, no. 5 / A. Gretchaninoff. -- Leipzig: Belaieff, 1934., Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich, 1864-1956; 1 score (2 p.) + 1 part (1 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 179)
      Plate no: 3394
      Transcribed for violin and piano by Thomas de Hartmann.
    - [Chant au rouet, arr.] Chant au rouet de F. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 1 score (6 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 111)
    - [Chant au rouet, arr.] Le chant au rouet., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 1 score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - [Chant au rouet, arr.] Le chant au rouet., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 1 score (6 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - [Chant populaire, arr.] Chant populaire de F. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 1 score (2 p.); 33 cm. (Box 17, Folder 111)
      Manuscript, photocopy
      Transcribed by Thomas de Hartmann for cello.